RAMON **RAMOS III**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- □ rj.ramos@gmail.com
- arjis02.github.io
- **** 732-895-1996
- **♀** Jersey City, NJ
- **y** aRJeRamos
- in ramonramos3
- arjis02

Skills

LANGUAGES

Ruby

JavaScript

FRONT END

HTML

CSS

ZURB Foundation

WEB FRAMEWORKS

Rails

Sinatra

TESTING FRAMEWORKS

RSpec

Capybara

DATABASE

ActiveRecord

SQL(PostgreSQL, SQLite)

VERSION CONTROL

GIT

METHODOLOGIES

Object-Oriented Design Test Driven Development

Behavior Driven Development

Agile

Education

Dev Bootcamp Graduate Full-Stack 2015

Rutgers School of Engineering

BS in Computer and Electrical Engineering 2005

Summary

I am an engineer with 10 years of experience in business development. I, recently, acquired the knowledge to build full-stack web applications. And, I am very comfortable working in groups and/or delegating work for a team. I have a passion for new technology and strive to learn what is relevant to be a major contributor to cutting edge technologies.

Projects

DreamCatcher

Social web application platform for users to share their dream experiences and assist others to increase their chances of experiencing lucid dreams.

Slack Overflow

Minimal version of Stack Overflow.

Survey Rose

Web application that allows users to create online surveys.

SOC Medical Equipment

Company website displaying their products and services.

Employment

Sleep On Call, Inc.

Middlesex, NJ

Director of Operations

lan 2009 to Oct 2014

- Streamlined day-to-day operations to obtain peak performance from three office locations
- · Negotiated with product vendors to maintain low inventory costs
- Increased product output by 103% from 2008-2009 with a minimal 3% increase in labor expenses
- Assisted walk-in customers and dealt with high level complaints resulting in increased customer satisfaction
- Produced quarterly reports on company performance and projected growth output to aid in managerial decisions
- Managed the company's network server (Windows Server 2008); set up and maintained all computers within the network resulting in increased employee output and efficient workflow
- Created, managed, and maintained company website making the company, its products, and services visible on the internet

Middlesex, NJ

Office Manager

- Apr 2006 to Dec 2008 · Facilitated completion of daily tasks with office and warehouse staff to ensure employee efficacy
- Created purchase orders to maintain required inventory
- Contacted patients for compliance data and reported information to physicians
- Effectively scheduled and coordinated daily deliveries to facilities and patients' homes
- Received and addressed customer complaints to full customer satisfaction

Middlesex, NJ

lun 2004 to Mar 2006

Senior HME Technician

- Trained new HME Technicians to meet exemplary company standards
- · Performed various warehouse duties including maintenance and organization
- · Delivered, assembled, trained, and serviced home medical equipment to highest standards
- · Communicated with patients and customers to address equipment inquiries and solve problems
- · Coordinated equipment deliveries with therapists, customers, and physicians to maintain client satisfaction